# LEONARD TNG

leonardtng@u.yale-nus.edu.sg • 10 College Avenue West

I am a penultimate year computer science student that has 3 years of software engineering experience. With a mindset of curiosity and the eagerness to challenge myself, I learn fast, enjoy working in teams, and can quickly adapt to any new environment or work setting.

#### Education

#### Yale-NUS College, Singapore • Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

2020 - 2024

Global Leader Scholar, <u>CAP: 4.84/5.0</u>

## National Junior College, Singapore • Integrated Programme • GCE 'A' Levels

2012 - 2017

MOE Pre-U Scholar, 90 Rank Points, 6 Distinctions

Experience

#### TikTok / ByteDance • Software Engineer Intern (Machine Learning Systems)

December 2021 - December 2022

- Developed and maintained a data visualisation and analysis tool for the company's internal machine learning platform. The tool is now heavily used by data scientists and machine learning engineers throughout the organisation, cutting software costs by over 80% through reducing the company's reliance on similar external software tools.
- Built an administrative dashboard to allow fast and easy monitoring of users on the company's data platform. This has thus far saved hundreds of hours for the research and development team in trying to track and understand user behaviour.
- Contributed to the overall codebase through heavy involvement in platform maintenance and updates based on user feedback.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Python, Flask, Ant Design, Apache ECharts

# Dathena • Software Engineer Intern (Product)

May 2021 – August 2021

- Developed and enhanced key sections of the client-facing data protection dashboard that increases the product's functionality to display complex data and provide key insights. Contributions were merged into production to serve the company's clients.
- Contributed to the internal UI-library by creating reusable components, writing the documentation, and implementing unit tests. Reduces future development time and streamlines the frontend release workflow. Led two sprints as scrum master.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Redux, styled components, D3.js, React Testing Library.

# Boogle Group Ltd. • Software Engineer Intern

October 2019 – September 2020

- Leveraged on full-stack technologies to build a web-based analytics dashboard that allow clients to visualise search query data.
- Teaching assistant at NTU as part of an educational partnership to boost the company's image and visibility.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Django REST Framework, AWS.

# Software Projects

#### Cryptoscapes: <a href="https://www.cryptoscapes.org/">https://www.cryptoscapes.org/</a>

- Built and hosted a web-based dashboard that manipulates and displays cryptocurrency data and charts.
- Ensured efficient data flow throughout components with global state management and atomic design methodology.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Redux, AWS (S3).

# CodeCache: <a href="https://www.codecache.io/">https://www.codecache.io/</a>

- Built and hosted a web application that allows users to create, edit, delete, and view code snippets.
- Developed a RESTful API backend architecture that manages and interacts with code snippets in a MySQL database.
- Implemented token authentication and email verification via SMTP for user login and registration.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Django REST Framework, MySQL, Docker, AWS (S3, EC2, RDS).

# Personal Website: <a href="https://www.leonardtng.com">https://www.leonardtng.com</a> (view for additional information and projects)

- Built and hosted a personal portfolio website with a responsive design and a multiple theme switcher.
- Performed search engine optimisation on website to obtain a high Google search ranking.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, AWS (S3).

## Leadership & Clubs

#### Yale-NUS Hacks (YNC\_Hacks) • Vice-President

December 2020 – January 2022

- Conducted two semester-long web development workshops and a three-part React.js workshop for over 20 new members.
- Oversaw the development processes of three club projects and facilitated project leaders to meet their project's milestones.

# Technical Skills

Programming Languages: (Proficient): TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, (Familiar): R, Scala, OCaml Frameworks / Technologies: (Proficient): React.js, Next.js, Express, Django REST Framework, Flask (Familiar): MongoDB, MySQL Utilities: Amazon Web Services (S3, CloudFront, Route 53, EC2, EB, ACM, Lambda, RDS), Docker, Git, GitHub, Jira, Bitbucket, Figma

# Contact

Website: www.leonardtng.com • LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/leonard-tng/ • GitHub: www.github.com/leonardtng